# PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a Mexican software developer with a passion for UI / UX. I really enjoy turning ideas into interactive software that entices the user to play. My main aptitude has been my dedication and attention to detail in all of my projects. I enjoy collaborating with my team, especially designers since I can fully understand their ideas and turn them into applications.

#### **EDUCATION**

MSc In Computer Science with an Specialization in Multimedia

University of Alberta, 2017 – 2019 http://mmgrad.org/.

### B.S., Software Engineering

Autonomous University of Yucatan, 2012 – 2016 http://www.uady.mx/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Front-End Developer

Edmonton, CA. June 2019 - Now

I worked as a Front-End developer in <u>gskinner.com</u>. I mainly worked as Flutter and Web developer through various projects.

## Web Developer

Edmonton, CA. February 2019 - May 2019

I worked as a full-stack web developer in Naik AR in a Virtual fitting application. The goal was for the end-user to visualize their eyewear on themselves before committing to a purchase. This reduces costs associated with product returns and improves customer satisfaction. It was used Unity, threeJS, Angular 7, Jeeliz among others.

# Internship AMMI Lab: Surgical Planner

Edmonton, CA.

May 2018 - December 2018

I worked in the University of Alberta AMMI Lab with Dr. Pierre Boulanger in the development of a Unity program that visualizes medical data in a collaborative virtual room for surgical planning.

# Front-End Developer

Merida, MX / Palo Alto, USA. August 2016 - August 2017.

I worked as a front-end developer at Kwan Tecnologia.

Outsourcing for TIBCO Software in the UX department.

### Summer research program.

College Station, USA. August 2016.

Presentation of scholarly research at the 2016 Engineering Summer Undergraduate Research Symposium. "Sequencing Technologies and their applications". Working with Dr. Noushin Ghaffari. Texas A&M University.

# SOFTWARE RELATED KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

Flutter, Dart, HTML 5, CSS, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, React, vue.js JQuery, Angular 7, Unity, Git.

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish

Native

#### English

TOEFLIBT SCORE: 91 R:23 L:25 W:20 S:23

## French

Institutional Language Center, Autonomous University of Yucatan (UADY) 2013 – 2015.